本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 卢尔摩斯 贝尔 苏三 up~per 晓月初白
校对： 海之南  后期： 海之南
《心灵缉凶》前情提要
Previously on Cracked
雷德利医生在您面前
What kinds of things would
是怎样评价布莱克警官的
Dr. Ridley tell you about Detective Black?
她会定期向我汇报艾登的心理状况
She would keep me apprised of Aidan's state of mind.
艾登 真的对不起
Aidan, I'm really sorry.
我无法再这样继续下去了
I can't do this anymore.
你造成的 你自己解决
You broke it, you have to fix it.
在另行通知之前 艾登 你和里奥一组
Until further notice, Aidan, you're partnered with Leo.
- 波比 你和丹妮拉一组 - 什么
- Poppy, you're with Daniella. - What?
- 我看过现场报告了 - 放下武器 伙计
- I read the scene report. - Put it down, buddy!
布莱克警探用枪瞄准一个嫌疑犯
Detective Black had his weapon trained on a suspect,
然后嫌疑犯跑掉了
and then the suspect ran away.
艾登肯定有什么事
Something happened with Aidan.
我不知道他脑子里怎么想的
I don't know where his mind went,
但是他走神了几秒钟
but he was gone for several seconds.
像是创伤后精神压力综合症
Looked like post-traumatic stress.
这很严重
This is serious.
我射伤了某人 但我却没得到我想要的结果
I shot someone. I didn't get the result that I was hoping for.
你需要问你自己
The question you need to ask yourself is:
你是否还胜任你的工作
Are you still doing your job well?
嘿 小姑娘 你还好吗
Hey, little girl, you OK?
一对夫妇发现她走得有点晕乎乎的
So, a couple noticed her walking around sort of dazed.
他们想靠近她 她就钻到椅子下面了
They approached her, she ducks under here.
我不知道怎么办
I don't know.
我试着哄她出来 但是她越抓越紧
I tried coaxing her out, but she just keeps holding on tighter.
- 有人报案丢孩子了吗 - 没有
- Anyone report a missing child? - No.
嗨 我是里奥 我是个护工
Hi, I'm Leo. I'm a nurse.
你介意我坐你旁边吗
Do you mind if I sit next to you?
然后你就找罪案心理分析科  为什么
And you called Psych Crimes. Why?
不然怎么办
Why not?
我的确看到这儿有个精神不正常的
Well, I can see the psych here, but...
但是没看到犯罪啊
not so much crime.
我只剩下一片了
It's my last piece.
知道吗 我总是和我孩子说
You know, I tell my kids all the time
不能躺着吃口香糖 会噎住的
that they can't chew gum laying down or else they'll choke.
所以要是你坐起来 最后一片就给你
So if you can sit up, the last piece is yours.
你说呢
What do you say?
想坐我旁边吗
Want to sit next to me?
看到那边的警官了吗
See the police officer over there?
那是我搭档 所以你很安全
That's my partner, so you're safe.
那么 你叫什么名字
So, what's your name?
喔 好冷啊
Ooh, it's cold.
啊
Ah.
我给你围上 好吗
How about I put this around you, OK?
很高兴认识你 奥利维亚
Nice to meet you, Olivia.
查理爸爸一号 学校登记录上记载
Papa Charlie-1, school records list
学生奥利维亚・华莱士家住罗克斯伯勒巷182号
182 Roxborough Lane for student Olivia Wallace.
奥利维亚 我们在这儿很安全
We're safe here, Olivia, OK?
能告诉我你和谁一起住吗
Can you tell me who you live with?
奥利维亚 告诉我谁在你的房子里
Olivia, can you tell me who's in your house?
我搭档现在在你家
My partner is in your house.
有什么他需要知道的吗
Is there anything he needs to know?
艾登
Aidan.
里奥
Leo.
打给急救中心 带那个女孩去医院
Call EMS. Take the girl to the hospital.
陪着她 然后给加利格拉打电话
Stay with her, and call Caligra.
跟她说 我需要雷德利
Tell her I need Ridley.
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 对上帝发誓 我看不见我的脸 #
Swear to God I couldn't see my face
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 注视着一缕灵魂 #
Staring at a ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了吗 #
Oh, have you seen my ghost
# 看到了吗 看到了吗 #
Seen my ghost, seen my ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了吗 #
Oh, have you seen my ghost
# 它凝视着地面 #
Staring at the ground
心灵缉凶 第一季第13集
死者名叫奥斯卡・华莱士 三十九岁
His name's Oscar Wallace... age 39,
历史学教授 航海发烧友 儿童棒球教练
history professor, avid sailor, kids' baseball coach.
他妻子三周前去了非洲
His wife's been in Africa for three weeks.
- 她本该今天早上回来的 - 去旅行还是别的
- She's due back this morning. - Safari or something?
不是 她是位人权律师
No, she's a human rights lawyer.
艾思梅・贝尔克 你听说过她吗
Esme Belk. Have you heard of her?
根据邻居们的说法
I guess she's famous or something,
我猜她应该很有名气
according to the neighbours.
脖子周围有勒痕
Circumferential laceration on his neck.
貌似是用绳索勒死的
It looks like ligature strangulation.
九岁大的孩子早上起来 想要的只是个华夫饼
Nine years old and you wake up, all you want is a waffle.
这么说 你和雷德利又开始搭档了
So, uh, you and Ridley are partners again?
没有 我只是需要她的头脑
No, I just need her brain on this.
嗨
Hi.
真是惨绝人寰
The brutality is striking.
没错 肩膀上有擦伤
Yeah, bruising on the shoulder.
肯定是踩住了胳膊
Must have just stepped on the arm
还抓住了手腕
and grabbed the wrist.
紧接着是难以忍受的疼痛
Unbearable pain ensued...
除非他的胳膊是死后被扭断的
unless he snapped the arms post mortem,
但我认为是死前被扭断的
but I'm thinking ante mortem.
- 为什么 - 你看 这么好的房子
- Why? - Well, it's a nice house,
他应该很有钱 行凶者也许想要图财
he's got money; Killer probably wanted some of it.
如果真的是想敲诈
There's easier parts of the body to break
还有更容易下手的身体部位
if extortion's the name of the game.
"给我钱 不然我就卸了你的胳膊"
"Give me the money or I'll break your arms."
先一边 然后另一边
First one, then the other.
然后他的头使劲上下挣扎 于是行凶者
Then his head's bobbing up and down, so the killer slips
找了根绳子勒住他的脖子 然后
a ligature around his neck, and then
就只剩下了无边的黑暗
it's nothing but darkness.
胳膊肯定是在传达一个信息
The arms, they gotta be a message,
是在暗示什么 一个标志 它们想表达什么呢
an allusion to something, a sign. What do they signify?
艾登 加利格拉说是你让我来这儿的
Aidan, Caligra said that you wanted me here with you,
但是我不
but I don't...
我们在这儿做什么呢 艾登
What are we doing here, Aidan?
死尸一具 怪异的双臂
Dead guy, weird arms?
我以为你集中注意了
I thought you were paying attention.
这是我家
This is my house.
- 艾思梅・贝尔克・华莱士吗 - 是我 发生什么了
- Esme Belk Wallace? - Yes. What's going on?
我女儿呢 奥斯卡呢
Where's my daughter? Where's Oscar?
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 她怎么样 - 你是她叔叔吗
- How is she? - You're her uncle?
- 是的 艾略特・贝尔克 - 里奥・贝克特
- Yeah, Elliott Belk. - Leo Beckett.
我们通过电话 呃 奥利维亚还没缓过来
We spoke on the phone. Um... Olivia's still in shock.
在某种程度上她能作出回应
She's responsive to a degree,
但是她还是不愿开口说话
but she's not talking yet,
我们还在等你姐姐的电话
and we're still waiting for your sister to call.
她的邻居说她出差了
Her neighbour said that she's away on business?
呃 没错 她本该今天早上回来的
Uh, yeah, she's supposed to be back this morning.
- 我能进去吗 - 可以
- Can I? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
嘿 宝贝儿 嗨
Hey, sweetheart. Hi.
嘿 我是艾略特叔叔
Hey, it's Uncle Elliott.
你怎么样了
How you doing?
我希望 一些熟人和安慰 或许会让她快点好过来
I'm hoping, with some familiarity and some comfort, that she'll come around soon.
嘿 不会有事的
Hey, it's gonna be OK.
我们有什么线索
So, what do we got?
死者的妻子 那个人权律师
Victim's wife, the human rights lawyer.
- 没错 艾思梅 - 我们拿到了她的旅行记录
- Yeah, Esme. - We got her travel records.
她在刚果待了三周 对吧
She's been in the Congo for three weeks, right?
你说她的航班是今早八点到的
You said her flight arrived at 8am this morning?
- 没错 - 事实并非如此 她的航班是昨天早上八点的
- Yup. - It didn't. Her flight got in at 8am  yesterday morning.
我一个小时前才看见她
I just watched her climb out
从机场豪华轿车上下来 带着行李之类的
of an airport limo an hour ago, luggage and everything.
这么说 除非艾思梅・贝尔克的记录出错了
Well, either Esme Belk's records are wrong,
不然她肯定在撒谎
or she likes to dabble in deception.
那么过去的二十四小时她在哪儿
Well, where's she's been for the last 24 hours?
- 你去哪儿 - 带她过来
- Where you headed? - To bring her in.
你去吗
Are you going?
搞什么名堂 你们一起工作可你不去
What's the deal? You guys are working together but you're not?
不晓得
I don't know.
他们一起离开了黑文谷
And together they left Valley Haven.
开始了森林之行
They journeyed deep into the woods
穿过冰冷的丛林雪堆
through icy trees and snow drifts,
经过日日夜夜
through day and night,
最终发现了他们仁慈的国王的家
until they finally came upon the home of their benevolent ruler.
他们慢慢走近房子
And they slowly walked up to the house
在敲门之前 他们脱掉雪地鞋
and took off their snowshoes, leaned 'em up against the wall
并将它们靠墙根摆放好
before knocking on the door.
她怎么样了
How's she doing?
她时不时会用眼神与我交流 但就是不肯讲话
She's making eye contact once in a while, but she's still not talking.
嘿 艾思梅在哪儿 为什么她没有来
Look, where's Esme? Why isn't she here?
据我所知 她正在警局接受调查
As far as I know, she's at headquarters talking to our investigators.
我不想离开奥利维亚
Look, I don't want to leave Olivia,
但是我有...有个工程计划图
but I have this... this work project
原本应该... 一小时前完成的
that was due... about an hour ago.
嘿 如果你想离开 没关系的
Hey, if you need to duck out, it's no trouble at all.
我会陪着她
I'll stay with her.
那好吧
OK.
嘿 宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
我会很快回来 好吗
I'm gonna be back soon, OK?
有事马上通知我
Call me the minute anything changes.
谢了
Thanks.
艾思梅 你想到有谁可能会杀害
Esme, can you think of anyone who would want to kill
你的丈夫吗
your husband?
我会列个清单给你 请带我去见我女儿
I'll make you a list. Please take me to see my daughter.
还有清单
There's a list?
我会收到死亡恐吓 一年有好几次
I get death threats, a couple a year.
大部分是针对我丈夫...或者奥利维亚
Mostly they're aimed at my husband... or Olivia.
如今他们动手了 他们威胁到了你的家人
That's how they do it nowadays; They threaten your family.
我们外出度假的时候 保安也会放假
We go on vacation, security guards go on vacation too.
这么说 你是刚从刚果回来
So, you just got back from the Congo?
是的 为期三周的目击证人采访
Uh, yes. Three weeks of witness interviews there.
他们不愿上海牙法庭 所以我去找他们
They won't go to the Hague, so I go to them.
荷兰城市海牙 国际战犯法庭所在地
在你离开期间 思念奥利维亚吗
Do you miss Olivia when you go away?
当然
Of course.
很久以前 我才终于学会接受
I came to terms a long time ago with the guilt
作为职业母亲与之俱来的那种愧疚that goes hand in hand with being a working mother.
你是何时从刚果回来的
When did you get back from the Congo?
我不知道...
I don't know...
你早上遇到我的 九点钟的样子
You saw me this morning, what, 9am?
没错 那你的航班什么时候到达的
Right, but when did your flight arrive?
- 早上八点 - 是今天早上吗
- Eight am. - This morning?
- 是的 - 可是
- Yes. - It's just,
你的旅行记录表明你是昨天早上到达的
your travel records state you arrived yesterday morning.
好吧 等等
OK, hang on a sec.
我没有...
I did not...
我整晚都在国宾酒店里
I was at the Ambassador Hotel all night.
2116房间 你可以去问门卫
Room 1126. You can ask the concierge.
好吧 如此来说 你在三周都没见到
OK, so, you fly home after not seeing your daughter
丈夫和女儿的情况下飞回家 却...
and your husband for three weeks, but...
没有马上去见他们
you don't go see them right away?
是的 我的工作很不易 打交道的都是一些战犯
Yes. My work is difficult. I deal with war criminals,
独裁者和受迫害者
dictators, torture victims.
我早已下定决心
I decided a long time ago
我绝不将工作带回家
that I was not going to bring that home to my family,
所以我在国宾酒店待了一晚
so I take a night at the Ambassador
梳理了一下头绪
to clear my head.
你是在指控我谋杀亲夫吗
Are you charging me with my husband's murder?
那么我想见见自己的女儿 就现在
Then I want to see my daughter. Now.
我看看能不能帮上忙
I'll see what I can do.
她在撒谎
She's lying.
- 撒谎不意味就犯法 - 意味着猜测变成现实了
- Lying doesn't mean guilty. - It means shit just got real.
她没有那么大的力气 弄折自己丈夫的手臂
She's not strong enough to break her husband's arms.
但是她的经济条件足以雇人作案
But she's rich enough to pay someone to do it for her.
你这是在干什么
What are you doing?!
不要 不要
No, no, no.
No! No!
不要 不要
第一位嫌疑人
Door number one:
坦艾民 缅甸国籍
Aye Min Than. Burmese national.
去年往她家客厅窗户里扔了一枚手榴弹
Threw a grenade through her living room window last year.
虽然不是真手榴弹 但还是扔了
Wasn't real, but still.
第二位嫌疑人 戈伦・米洛维奇
Door number Two: Goran Milovic.
塞尔维亚人 几年前在住宅外被捕
A Serbian. He was arrested outside the house
当时艾思梅正为一位克罗地亚叛军领袖辩护
a few years ago when Esme was defending a Croat rebel leader.
他在他们家前院纵火烧树
He set fire to a tree in their front yard.
- 她手头上的案子呢 - 那是第三个嫌疑人:
- What about her current case? - Door number three:
艾尼沃克・阿德伊米 加拿大落地移民
Enioke Adeyemi. He's a landed immigrant,
祖籍刚果民主共和国
originally from the Democratic Republic of the Congo.
他的母亲和姐姐都是前儿童军的受害者
His mother and sister were victims of the former child soldier.
艾思梅的辩护方 法西纳・戈翁
Esme's defending, Fasina Gowon.
这家伙在八岁时
The guy was enslaved to the Lord's Resistance
沦为圣主抵抗军的奴隶 期间被洗脑
Army when he was eight, and brainwashed.
阿德伊米先生几周前在咖啡厅遇到艾思梅 便对她大吼大叫
Mr. Adeyemi confronted Esme at a café a few weeks ago, started yelling;
当时他携带了把小折刀 但是没有使用
He had a pocket knife on him, but he didn't use it.
这些还只是没入狱 也没被驱逐出境的嫌疑人
And these are just the suspects that aren't in jail or deported already.
为什么还没带艾思梅・贝尔克去看她的女儿
Why has Esme Belk not been taken to see her daughter?
因为她在撒谎 所以我给她时间
Because she's lying, so I'm stalling to give her time
在里面细想一下监禁的滋味
to ponder what incarceration is gonna look like from the inside.
除非我们控告她 否则我们就得放人
We can't keep her any longer unless we charge her.
你可以让她在去医院的路上好好想想
You can let her ponder on the way to the hospital.
奥利维亚
Olivia?
宝贝儿
Sweetheart?
- 妈妈 - 哦
- Mom. - Oh!
我被尖叫声惊醒
I woke up 'cause there was screaming,
我手足无措
and I didn't know what to do,
于是就躲进了被窝里
so I hid under the covers,
当我下楼到大厅时 我听到有人像是在跑
and when I walked down the hall, I heard somebody, like, running,
接着就听到了关门声...
and I heard the door shut...
于是我了下楼
and then I went down the stairs,
我看到...
and I saw...
没事了 没事了
It's OK, it's OK.
没事了 宝贝
It's OK, sweetheart.
我太对不起你了
I'm so sorry.
我应该陪在你身边
I should have been there.
奥利维亚 你昨晚没有参加你朋友家的彻夜狂欢吗
Olivia... didn't you go to a sleepover last night?
你爸爸上周给我发短信
Your Daddy texted me
说你受邀参加一个彻夜狂欢派对 你没有去吗
last week that you got invited to a sleepover. You didn't go?
我去了 后来我有点害怕
I went, except I got scared later,
所以劳伦的爸爸就送我回家了
so Lauren's dad drove me home.
奥利维亚 你到家时 你爸爸在哪里
Olivia, when you got home, where was your dad?
看电视
Watching TV.
他把我抱进卧室 还说 "爱你 丽维亚小乖乖"
He tucked me in and said, "Love you, Livia-bug."
没事了 小南瓜 不要说了
It's OK, Pumpkin. Shh, shh.
没事了 没事了
It's OK, it's OK.
这么看来 凶手听到奥利维亚下床
So, the killer heard Olivia get out of bed.
让他很吃惊 随即逃走
It surprised him, and he ran.
- 他原本以为有更多时间 - 更神不知鬼不觉
- He thought he had more time. - And more privacy.
有可能他本不知道奥利维亚在家
Could be he didn't know Olivia was there,
或者根本不知道奥斯卡有个孩子
or even that Oscar had a kid.
抑或是他清楚奥利维亚的安排 知道她不会在家
Or he knew Olivia's schedule and knew she wasn't gonna be at home.
她听到尖叫后被惊醒
And she woke up because she heard him screaming,
这么说他的手臂是在死前被折断的
so his arms were broken before he died.
没错 你要留下来吗
Yup. You sticking around?
恩 再待会儿
Yeah, for a bit.
我想看看奥利维亚还能不能回忆起什么来
I'm gonna see if Olivia can remember anything else.
- 好吧 - 艾登 等等
- OK. - Aidan, wait.
我不想再这样在你身边工作 而不和你搭档
I don't want to go on working near you and not with you,
所以要是我们再也不能搭档了
so if we can't ever be partners again,
你可以现在就告诉我吗
can you just let me know now?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
噢 你好
Oh, hi.
对不起 我是丹妮拉・雷德利
Sorry. I'm Daniella Ridley,
和警察共事的精神科医生 你是和华莱士家一起的吗
a psychiatrist with the police. Are you with the Wallace family?
对 对 我叫艾略特・贝尔克.
Uh, yeah, yeah, I'm Elliott Belk.
- 你好 - 你好 是艾思梅的哥哥
- Hi. - Hi. Uh, Esme's brother,
奥利维亚的舅舅
uh, Olivia's uncle.
- 里面都还好吧 - 嗯
- Everything all right in there? - Well, uh,
奥利维亚睡着了 艾思梅在里面陪她 所以...
Olivia's finally asleep, and Esme's in there with her, so...
好吧 那正好趁现在 我可以问你一些
OK, well, maybe now would be a good time if I could ask you
关于你妹妹和她家人的问题吗
some questions about your sister and her family?
好 当然
Uh, yeah, yeah, sure.
你和奥斯卡亲近吗
Were you and Oscar close?
我可能和奥利维亚最亲近
Well, uh, I was probably closest with Olivia.
艾思梅经常出差
You know, Esme goes out of town all the time,
奥斯卡晚上又要上课
and Oscar teaches his night classes,
就经常由我来照看奥利维亚
so I end up babysitting for Olivia a fair bit.
她有你陪着真是幸运
Oh. She's lucky to have you.
是吗 我倒不知道
Ah, yeah, I don't know about that.
我们有一个只有我俩才懂的笑话
Um, we have this little inside joke
她不叫我"艾略特叔叔"
where she doesn't call me "Uncle Elliott",
- 而是叫我"不代家叔叔" - "不代家"?
- she calls me "Uncle LPS". - LPS?
就是"不称职代理家长"
Yeah, "Lame Parental Substitute".
消灭所有巧克力碎片饼干的总是我
You see, I'm the guy that burns all the chocolate chip cookies,
给她读床前故事的时候 我反而先睡着
and I end up falling asleep while I'm reading her the bedtime stories.
艾思梅 待她真的很不错
Esme, uh, Esme's really great with her,
但是 她总是不在家
but, you know, she's gone all the time.
我们还是很为她骄傲的 因为她在外面
We're really proud of her for that, because she's out there,
努力让世界变得更完美
you know, making the world a nicer place to live.
不过 我就不班门弄斧了
But look who I'm talking to, right?
什么意思
Um, what do you mean?
你说你是警察局的精神病专家对吗
You said you're a psychiatrist with the police department,
那一定很忙吧
right? That's gotta be really demanding...
在需要的时候和人沟通 帮助他们度过难关
talking to people when they really need you, helping them through tragedy.
我...我怎么能和你妹妹
I'm... I'm nowhere near the league
相提并论呢
your sister's in.
艾登 我们刚刚抓到了艾尼沃克・阿德伊米
Aidan, we just picked up Enioke Adeyemi.
那个父母被艾思梅辩护的童子兵杀害的家伙吗
The guy's parents who were killed by the child soldiers she's defending?
- 对 就是他 - 另外两个呢
- Yeah, that's the one. - What about the other two?
其中一个已经逃出国 另外一个死了
Well, it turns out one of them's out of the country, and the other one's dead.
法医从华莱士家的滑门玻璃上
Forensics just lifted Adeyemi's prints
提取到了阿德伊米的指纹
off the sliding glass doors at the Wallace house.
在B审讯室
Interrogation Room B.
- 嗨 里奥 你要去哪儿 - 我要跟她走
- Hey, Leo, where are you going? - I'm going with her.
- 你要甩掉我吗 - 给我打电话吧
- Oh, you're dumping me? - Call me sometime.
我在孤儿院长大 然后来到这里
I was raised in an orphanage, and then I come here,
然后有了工作 有了朋友
and I am working, and I have friends,
然后我看到了报纸
and then I read the newspaper.
法西纳・戈翁 难民 改造后的
Fasina Gowon. Refugee, reformed
童子军 一个自由的人
child soldier, a free man.
但他杀了我的家人
But he killed my family,
而艾思梅・贝尔克在为他辩护
and Esme Belk is defending him.
每个人应该被公平对待
Everyone deserves a fair trial.
他绝不是受害者
He is no victim.
你周三晚上在哪里
Where were you Wednesday night?
我们知道你想跟踪艾思梅
We know you like to follow Esme.
好吧 我们知道你跟踪她 你知道她的行程
OK, we know you stalk her, you know her schedule,
你知道她很多事情
you know a lot of things about her.
你也会知道什么时候是进去杀她丈夫的最佳时机
You would know when the best time is to go in and kill her husband.
我为什么要杀人呢
Why would I kill someone?
为了让她也体会到失去家人的感觉
To make her know what it feels like to lose family.
我在值班
I was on shift.
你可以检查下我车上的GPS导航仪
You can check the GPS in my cab.
- 马上去核实 - 我们已经着手核实了
- Verify with dispatch. - We're doing that already.
好吧 你们听好了
OK, you listen now.
我越跟踪艾思梅・贝尔克
The more I follow Esme Belk,
我越了解到她不是什么好人
the more I know she is not a good person.
你们都觉得这个女人是个优秀的人权律师 是个圣人
You all think that this woman is a good human rights lawyer, that she is a saint,
但你们并不了解她
but you don't know her.
你们不了解她
You don't know her.
艾尼沃克
Enioke.
我们不了解她什么
What don't we know?
- 不好意思 是阿利斯泰尔・科普兰德吗 - 是我
- Excuse me. Alistair Coupland? - Yes.
我是都市警察局的艾登・布莱克警探
I'm Detective Aidan Black. I'm with the Metro Police.
怎么了
What's going on?
你知道奥斯卡・华莱士被谋杀了吗
Are you aware that Oscar Wallace was found murdered?
知道 整个学院都很悲痛
Yes, the entire faculty is devastated.
你知道他的妻子艾思梅
Did you know that his wife Esme
被一个刚果来的男人跟踪吗
was being stalked by a man from the Congo?
知道
Yes.
我们问过这个男人 他告诉我们
We spoke with this man, and he told us
不管她何时出差回来
that you pick her up at the airport
你都会去机场接她
whenever she returns home from a business trip?
你周三晚上和她一起 呆在国宾酒店吗
Were you with her at the Ambassador Hotel on Wednesday night?
是的 不要让我妻子知道好吗
Yes. Can we not involve my wife in this?
你怎么认识艾思梅的
How did you meet Esme?
在几年前的一个学院聚会上
A holiday faculty party a couple years ago.
对 她出差回来之后
And, yeah, we get together
我们一起在大使酒店相聚
at the Ambassador when she comes home from a trip.
- 周三晚上呢 - 我十二点半左右离开的
- And Wednesday night? - I left around 12:30.
我第二天在圭尔夫市有个会议
I had a conference in Guelph the next day...
路很远 要早起
long drive, early start.
你们可以问大楼的看门人
You can talk to my doorman at the building.
他可以确认
He'll confirm it.
所以你不知道艾思梅十二点半之后去哪里了吗
So you don't know where Esme was after 12:30?
艾思梅是个好人
Esme is a good person.
她很复杂 没错
She's complicated, yes,
但她敢做那些常人不理会的事
but she does things not everybody agrees with.
她不会杀人
She wouldn't kill someone.
她绝对不可能杀奥斯卡
She sure as hell wouldn't kill Oscar.
怎么说呢 艾思梅从小优生惯养
Well, what can I tell you? Esme grew up privileged...
玩的都是滑雪 帆船 骑马
downhill skiing, yachting, horseback riding,
上的是最好的私立学校
the best private schools.
艾思梅和你父母的关系如何
What was Esme's relationship like with your parents?
不错 对 不错
Good. Yeah, it was good.
具体是什么情况
Um, and what do you mean by "good"?
说实话
Um... to be honest with you,
我 具体不清楚
I, uh, heh, I don't know exactly.
艾思梅和我 并不是一块长大的
You see, Esme and I didn't grow up together.
我八岁的时候
When I was eight years old, my father shipped
父亲把我送去了瑞士的寄宿学校
me off to boarding school in Switzerland.
八岁 也太小了吧
At eight? That's very young.
是啊 我父亲不允许不优秀的存在
Yeah. Yeah, my father wouldn't accept anything less than excellence.
你觉得艾思梅达到他的期望了吗
Do you think Esme fulfilled his expectations?
反正她没被送去瑞士的寄宿学校
She didn't get sent to boarding school in Switzerland.
我不知道
I don't know.
事实上我有三十年没和艾思梅接触过了
You know, I've had virtually no contact with Esme for 30 years.
你三十年都没回过家吗
You never came back to your home for 30 years?
没有 毕业之后 我四处旅行
Mmmmm. No, after school, I travelled around for a bit,
最近的十年我都在各地工作
and I've travelled with work for the last 10 years.
那你到底有多了解她
How well would you say you know her, then?
还可以 听着 医生 为什么要问我这么多关于艾思梅的事
Pretty well. Look, Doc, why all these questions about Esme?
抱歉 我们必须搞清楚
I'm sorry, we have to be very thorough.
好吧 听着 我得回去看看奥利维亚
OK. Look, I should get back to Olivia.
好 当然 谢谢你
Yes, of course. Thank you.
没事 抱歉
Yeah. Excuse me.
好了 来吧 看奥斯卡・华莱士的通话记录
All right, here we go. Oscar Wallace's phone records.
这是艾思梅的电话
Esme's number.
好吧 他经常给艾思梅打电话 但是
All right, well, he called Esme a lot, but...
还有一个号码他上周也打得很勤
there's another number here he called a whole bunch in the last week.
他的办公室吗
His office?
奥斯卡也有个情人吗
Oscar had a lover of his own?
或者他在调查她的情人
Or he was on to hers.
这些电话都是打给一个叫卡斯帕的私人侦探
All these calls are to a private investigator. Kasper.
他在为离婚收集证据吗
He's gathering evidence for a divorce case?
收集你老婆和别人勾搭的照片 时机刚好
Getting photos of your wife hooking up with someone else. Good times.
所以如果他打算跟她离婚 而她发现
So if he was preparing to divorce her, she finds out...
- 他想要监护权 - 唔 动机来了
- He wants custody. - Boom. Motive.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我是艾登・布莱克警探 这位是丹妮拉・雷德利
I'm Detective Aidan Black. This is Daniella Ridley.
- 你是卡斯帕吗 - 啊 不 不是
- Are you Kasper? - Uh, no, no,
- 我是卡斯帕的助理 - 卡斯帕在楼上吗
- I'm Kasper's assistant. - Is Kasper upstairs?
- 他今天不在这儿 - 哦 也许你可以协助我们
- He's not here today. - Well, maybe you could help us.
我们在查找一些信息
We're looking for some information.
卡斯帕有个客户叫做奥斯卡・华莱士
Kasper has a client named Oscar Wallace.
很抱歉 我不能透露有关客户的信息
I'm sorry, I really can't talk about clients.
要是我告诉你奥斯卡・华莱士死了呢
What if I told you Oscar Wallace was dead?
他在昨天被人谋杀了
He was murdered yesterday.
奥斯卡的案子是不是和偷情有关
Was Oscar's case about infidelity?
奥斯卡・华莱士是不是怀疑他妻子背着他偷情呢
Did Oscar Wallace believe his wife was cheating on him?
我... 我不知道 我对这个案子真的
I... I don't know. I really don't know anything
什么也不知道 是卡斯帕负责接待华莱士的 所以...
about the case. Kasper was dealing with Wallace, so...
我们在哪可以找到卡斯帕
Where can we find Kasper?
他按说今天早上要过来的
Well, he was supposed to be here this morning
主持一些会议 但他没出现
to take some meetings, but he never showed,
而且现在他连电话也不接了
and now he's not answering his cell phone.
所以很奇怪 还有 唔...
So that's weird, and, uh...
我现在正准备去他家
I was just heading over to his house right now.
好的 唔... 要不我让你们进去吧
OK, shit, um... why don't I let you in?
在卡斯帕的办公室里有个档案盒
There's a case box in Kasper's office.
我知道你对翻看大堆的文件资料情有独钟
I know you've got a soft spot for overwhelming paperwork.
- 太好了 太谢谢你了 - 好吧 嘿 伙计
- Great. Thank you so much. - All right, hey, man,
你一把她安顿好了 就马上下来吧
when you're done setting her up, come on back down.
我要跟着你去你老板的家 怎么样
I'm gonna follow you to your boss' house, all right?
我在车站等你
I'll meet you at the station.
艾略特・贝尔克 三十五年前
E. Belk. Thirty-five years ago.
艾略特 你知道吗
Elliott, do you know
- 你为什么在这里吗 - 我爸爸送我来的
- why you're here? - 'Cause my dad made me come.
- 他为啥送你过来 - 因为他找到了那些鞋盒
- Why did he make you come? - 'Cause he found the shoeboxes.
- 那些鞋盒里有什么 - 一些鸟
- And what was in them? - Birds.
你是怎么把它们都抓进那里面的
How did you get them in there?
呃 我对抓东西挺在行的
Well, I'm really good at catching things.
我能不发出一点声音地走过去 我还可以...
I can sneak up really quiet, and I can...
抓住它们
just grab them.
你又是怎么弄伤它们的呢
How did you hurt them?
我抓住它们的翅膀然后...
I take their wings and...
好的 好的 明白 我知道了
OK, OK, yeah, got it.
艾登刚从私家侦探家里回来
Aidan just got back from the PI's house.
他在那找到了一个香港发来的文件
He found a file there from Hong Kong.
很明显  艾略特・贝尔克几年前在那里被抓了
Apparently, Elliott Belk was arrested there a few years ago.
等等  是艾略特・贝尔克
Wait, Elliott Belk?
对的 私家侦探并没有在调查艾思梅通奸的事
Yeah. The PI wasn't investigating Esme for adultery;
他是在调查她的哥哥
He was investigating her brother.
我听说你上周折断了些
I was told you broke some bigger bones
- 更大的骨头 - 是艾思梅的
- last weekend. - Esme's.
又是艾思梅 她还只是个婴儿啊
Esme's too? She's practically a baby.
- 你为什么要伤害她 - 啊
- Why did you hurt her? - Ah!
我只是在检查她的手臂 我想这么做
I was looking at her arm. And I wanted to.
她哭了
She cried.
- 现在 你是什么感觉 - 我很喜欢
- Now, how did that make you feel? - I liked it.
是的 我记得艾略特・贝尔克
Yes, I remember Elliott Belk.
他不是个你能轻易忘记的人
He's not a man you easily forget.
- 他被怀疑犯了什么罪 - 一级谋杀罪
- What was he suspected of? - First-degree murder.
那是五年前
It was about five years ago.
受害者是贝尔克先生的合作者之一
The victim was one of Mr. Belk's coworkers,
他在参加CXB银行的高管庆祝晚会后被杀了
And he was killed after a party for CXB Bank executives.
宋警官 你们当时怎么追查到贝尔克的呢
Detective Sung, what led you guys to pursue Belk?
他出席了那个晚会
He attended the party,
然后大楼监控录像也有拍到他
and he was caught on building security cameras
跟随受害者出了门
following the vicitim outside.
但最后 我们没有足够的物证去指控他
In the end, we did not have sufficient physical evidence to charge.
我们很想看看你的档案
We'd be really interested to look at your files.
要是能帮上你们 当然可以
If it will help, absolutely.
嘿 雷德利
Hey, Ridley.
我们在卡斯帕家里的桌上找到了一些文件
So, we found some papers in Kasper's desk at home.
看起来艾略特到处流窜啊...
Looks like Elliott bounced around a lot...
瑞士 香港 罗马 伦敦
Switzerland, Hong Kong, Rome, London.
他在苏黎世有段两年的婚姻 期间多次
He was married for two years in Zurich, had a couple
被指控使用家庭暴力 但后来就都不了了之了
of domestic violence charges, but those were dropped.
雷德利 不管怎样 回头打给我
Anyway, Ridley, call me back.
里奥
Leo.
- 嘿 雷德利 - 啊 不 我是达米安
- Hey, Ridley. - Uh, no, it's Damian.
你怎么用雷德利医生的电话
Why are you calling me
打给我 她人在哪儿
from Dr. Ridley's phone? Where is she?
我不知道 呃 她的东西和钱包都在这儿
I don't know. Uh, her things and her purse are here,
唯独华莱士的档案不见了
but the Wallace files are gone.
香港发来的犯罪现场照片
Crime scene photo from Hong Kong.
啊
Ugh!
- 啊 啊 - 救命
- Ugh! Ugh! - Help!
警官 这里还有很多
Inspector, there are more.
1999年在沙夫豪森 一个死在出租住房里的流浪者
Schaffhausen, '99. A drifter found dead in a rooming house.
沙夫豪森 瑞士境内靠近德国边界的一个小镇
艾略特・贝尔克当时就住在那里
Elliott Belk was living there at the time.
2001年在巴勒莫 英国游客
Palermo, 2001. A British tourist
巴勒莫 西西里首府
被发现死在以艾略特名字登记的旅馆房内
found dead in a hotel room under Elliott's name.
他们两人的手臂都被折断了
Both of them had their arms broken.
我们知道的还只是一小部分
And these are just a few that we know about.
你也许可以把私家侦探加上去
You might as well add that private investigator to the list.
我们在想艾略特回到卡斯帕的办公室
We're thinking Elliott went back to Kasper's office
去处理任何收集到的对他不利的证据
to get rid of any evidence collected against him,
却发现丹妮拉在那里
found Daniella there.
总之 我们对艾略特就知道这些
So, this is what we know about Elliott:
他喜欢把活人的手臂折断
He likes to break people's arms while they're still alive,
这让他成为一个施虐狂 也就是说
which probably makes him a sadist, which means
他看着他的受害者们受苦而感到兴奋
he gets a thrill from seeing his victims in pain,
所以他会让丹妮拉活着直到他感受到那种刺激
so he'll want to see Daniella alive until he gets that thrill.
要是她没能给他那种刺激呢
What if she doesn't give it to him?
如果说有人知道如何对付艾略特这样的人 那一定是丹妮拉
Well, if anybody knows how to handle a guy like Elliott, it's Daniella.
不管她面临多大的恐惧或者承受多大的痛苦
No matter how afraid she is or how much pain she's in,
她都会尽可能的坚持下去
she'll hold off as long as she can.
这是哪里
What is this place?
你喜欢看这些吗
Did you enjoy watching these?
不喜欢 但它们能帮助我明白些事
No, but they helped me understand.
帮助你明白什么
Helped you understand what?
明白了你的父母把你送走是为了保护艾思梅
That your parents sent you away to protect Esme.
也是为了躲着我
And kept me away.
其实从我在寄宿学校以名列前百分之五的成绩毕业后
After I graduated in the top 5% of boarding school,
我父亲就给我钱让我别再回家了
my father actually paid me to keep me from coming back home.
五年前 我错过了我母亲的葬礼
Five years ago, I missed my mother's funeral.
大约一年以前 我痛下决心
About a year ago, I made sure
会参加他的葬礼
to come back for his.
他现在估计在坟墓里也要气炸了
He's probably rolling over in his grave.
但我可以告诉你休想伤害艾思梅和奥利维亚
But I can tell you don't plan to hurt Esme and Olivia.
医生 你怎么能这么说呢
How can you tell that, Doc?
因为我还相信你愿意拥有亲人
Because I think you like having a family.
我还相信你愿意拥有那些欣赏你的人
I think you like having people who admire you.
那能让你感觉自己很正常 感到内心的和谐
I think it makes you feel normal, makes you blend in.
你为什么杀了奥斯卡
Why did you kill Oscar?
噢 奥斯卡
Oh, Oscar.
他看到奥利维亚这么快就喜欢上我所以嫉妒了
He got jealous that Olivia started to love me so quickly,
所以他请了个私家侦探尽可能地
so he hired a private investigator to try
去挖出任何东西把我从我妹妹身边赶走
and dig up anything he can to try and squeeze me out of my sister's life.
我本打算把他埋在屋后的山上 但是...
I was gonna bury him on the hill behind the house, but...
你根本没回答我的问题
You never answered my question.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我家
It's home.
你八岁之前的家
Until you were eight?
是的 我们一家在那住还不到十年
Yeah. It hasn't been in my family for decades,
但是 唔...
but, uh...
我很幸运 那个主人...死了
fortunately enough for me, the owner... died.
从我离开这里后
You know, after I left here,
我...我一直和自己做斗争
I... I tried to fight the urges.
是的 我大多数时候还是表现不错的
Yeah, I did pretty well for the most part.
但要自己装作
But it's just not easy
别的谁确实不容易啊
pretending to be somebody that you're not.
医生 对吗
Is it, Doc?
回家的感觉太好了
It feels so good to be home.
雷德利医生 我想让你看看奥斯卡・华莱士的私家侦探
Doctor Ridley, I'd like you to meet Oscar Wallace's snoop.
从小到大 别人一直跟我说艾略特很聪明
All my life, I was told that Elliott was smart
很特别 他只是...
and special, and that he was just...
没有上学 所以当我父亲去世时
away at school, so when my father died,
我... 我窃喜他又回到我身边来
I just... I was happy to have him back in my life.
我是说 你对我讲的这些 我不能...
I mean, what you're saying to me, I can't...
- 我是说... - 好了 艾思梅 我明白了
- I mean... - OK, Esme, I get it,
但是能否想一下 艾略特有没有提过
but just think for a second. Has Elliott mentioned any place
在他公寓附近 有没有他喜欢去的地方
beside his condo that he likes to go?
没有
No.
小木屋 储藏室... 或者其他地方
A cottage, storage space... anything.
他总是给我讲一个有关城堡的故事
He tells me stories about a castle.
- 奥利维亚 - 城堡
- Olivia... - A castle?
一个男孩和一个女孩住在那儿
About a boy and girl who live there.
他们经常在森林里冒险
They go on adventures in the woods.
他们穿着雪地靴
They wear snowshoes.
穿雪地靴的男孩和女孩
A boy and a girl snowshoeing.
我知道在哪儿了
I know where that is.
在米都维尔小巷十四号
The address is 14 Meadowvale Lane,
我想你肯定知道如果你被判施虐罪
I'm assuming you know what will happen to you if you get convicted
会有什么后果
of a crime involving sadism.
我当然知道
Of course I do.
但我不会被抓
But I'm not getting caught.
但是有可能
But you might.
好吧 万一被抓了
Oh, well, in that case,
我无需负法律责任
I would be found not criminally responsible,
我可能被送到某个悠闲的地方
I'd be sent to some cushy facility somewhere
跟别人围坐着聊天
where I would sit around in a circle and talk
谈论我本不该做的事情...
about how I shouldn't have done what I did and...
...然后去吃个午饭
...then I'd go have lunch.
但那根本不可能 艾略特
But that's not going to happen, Elliott.
你精神没有问题
You're not mentally ill.
你没有病
You don't have a disease.
没有药能改变你的行为
No amount of medication is ever gonna change your behaviour.
可能三十年后你会被送到那种悠闲的地方
Maybe 30 years ago you would have been sent to a facility like that,
但现在像你这样的人只能进监狱
but now they just send people like you to jail.
我要是没病 那我为什么这样
Well, if I'm not ill, then what am I?
你就是内心邪恶罢了
You're just bad.
你不能有点新意吗 医生
You don't have any fancier words for me, Doc?
可以
No, I do.
虐待狂 精神病患
Sadist. Psychopath.
怪物
Monster.
我这样待你的时候 希望能听到你的尖叫
I want you to scream when I do this to you.
我不会让你得逞的
I'm not gonna help you enjoy this.
你会的
Oh, yes, you will.
噢 不对我叫是吗
Oh, you're not gonna scream for me?
你想把我怎么样 像对别人一样掰断我的胳膊
What are you gonna do, break my arms like you did the others?
因为他们会让你想起小鸟折断翅膀的声音
'Cause they remind you of birds' wings?
我喜欢听那种声音
I like the sound that it makes.
来嘛
Now, come on.
让我听听你的尖叫
Let me hear you scream.
- 快叫 - 警察 艾略特
- Scream for me! - Police! Elliott!
别动 把刀放下
Don't move! Drop the knife, man!
放下你的枪 否则你知道我会怎么做
You drop your gun. You know what I'll do.
我不会放下枪 我们来谈谈
I'm not dropping this gun. You and I, we're gonna talk.
没什么好谈的
No talking.
给我
Give it to me!
快点 放下武器
Do it now! Drop that weapon!
你把枪放下
You drop the gun.
好的 好的
All right, all right, all right, all right.
我把枪放下
I'm gonna put the gun down.
你想要怎样 伙计
What do you need, man?
你想离开这里 要开我的车吗
You want to get out of here? You want my car?
我给你钥匙 你要什么我都给你
I'll give you the keys, I'll slide'em over, whatever you need.
我要你闭嘴 把枪踢过来
I need you to shut up and kick the gun over here.
快点 现在
Do it! Now!
好的 好的
All right, all right.
- 啊
- Ugh!
- 把他抓起来 - 丹妮拉 我是里奥
- Tag 'em, tag 'em. - Daniella, it's Leo.
我是里奥 你现在安全了 没事了
It's Leo. You're safe now. You're safe.
你还好吗
You OK?
雷德利 还好吗
Ridley, you OK?
怎么样 嘿 里奥 叫救援队过来
You OK? Are you OK? Hey, Leo, call it in.
没事了 你安全了 你安全了
It's OK. Hey, you're safe, you're safe, you're safe.
我是里奥・贝克特 和罪案心理分析科一起
OK. This is Leo Beckett with Psych Crimes.
我需要护理人员 在米都维尔小巷十四号
I need paramedics at 14 Meadowvale Lane.
嫌疑犯中枪了
Suspect's been shot.
我觉得他挺不过去了
I don't think he's gonna make it.
# 暴风雨即将来袭 #
A storm is coming
# 而我心平静 #
But I don't mind
# 人之将死 #
People are dying
# 我双眸轻闭 #
I close my blinds
# 只知晓 我仍在呼吸 #
All that I know is I'm breathing now
他们说我们无法掌控会发生什么事
They say that we can't control the things that happen to us,
但我们可以学会怎样去面对
but we can control the way we react to them.
我觉得"他们"错了
I say "they" are wrong,
因为没人控制得了创伤后应激障碍
'cause no one can control PTSD.
它只是做了你的心中所想
It just does what it wants to you.
但第二次在千钧一发之际幻觉重现时
But I can control how I react to the knowledge
我能控制住自己 知道该如何应对
that for the second time I had a flashback in a critical situation.
我的搭档身陷险境
My partner's life was at risk.
艾登 这次你产生了幻觉
Aidan, this time you had a flashback,
但你没有失控 你仍保持清醒
you didn't lose touch. You kept a clear head,
你明白了丹妮拉的暗示
you read Daniella's signals,
尽管你的每个细胞都叫嚣着
you did something
但你做了你该做的...
that every fibre in your body was telling you not to do...
你放下了枪
you put down your gun.
你没有单凭策略来做决定
And you didn't make those decisions through strategy.
这也体现了你的胆量和责任
It was also your gut and your trust.
你们心意相通 成功完成了任务
You did it with empathy and you got the job done.
这不是劫数
This is not doom
而是进步
This is progress.
现在 你...很称职
Now, you... are supposed to be here.
现在 回去好好工作吧
Now, please, get your ass back to work.
# 我只能静静呼吸 #
All I can do is keep breathing
破碎的信任感很难修复
Broken trust isn't easily mended.
这种感觉打心底儿感到可怕
It's just this awful feeling in the pit of my stomach.
- 这需要时间 - 嘿
- It's gonna take time. - Hey.
只有一种方法能消除隔阂
There's only one way to kill it.
我们再搭档一次吧
Let's try again.
# 我们只能静静呼吸 #
All we can do is keep breathing
好啊
OK.
# 我们只能静静呼吸 #
All we can do is keep breathing
这工作还真不赖
There's a lot of good in this job,
能有机会改变人们的生活
a chance to make a difference in people's lives,
但也有不少坏处
but there's a lot of bad too.
那个绑架我搭档的匪徒
The guy who kidnapped my partner,
就是个彻头彻尾的混蛋
he's a bad guy through and through.
那么 你最近觉得坏的一面远超过好的一面吗
So, do you feel lately the bad has eclipsed the good?
黑暗总比光明多 是这样吗
That there's more darkness than light?
# 我们只能静静呼吸 #
All we can do is keep breathing
我不知道 我是说...与坏处相比
I don't know, I mean... anything good
好处看起来总是...
just seems so...
那么渺小
small in comparison to all the bad
我...好不容易才看清这一点
that I... have a hard time seeing it.
布莱克警探
Detective Black.
好的
Yup.
好的 谢谢
OK, thank you.
艾略特死在医院了
Elliott died in hospital.
你看到的比一般人要多 艾登
You see more than most people, Aidan.
坏事发生在你身边 甚至就发生在你身上
Bad things happen near you, to you,
但是好事因你而发生
but good things happen because of you.
你想过也许这两方面源自同一种情感吗
Do you ever think maybe good and bad are part of the same single feeling?
怎么称呼这种情感呢
What would you call that feeling?
整体感
A sense of wholeness.
本季已完结 感谢大家对此剧的支持
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.com